Harvey Chalmers Papers
Harvey Chalmers Papers
1935-1971
Chalmers, Harvey.
10.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American author, novelist, short story writer; died 1971. Specialized in books relating to early New York State and United States history. Correspondence (1938-1971), manuscripts, notes, photographs, research material, and a scrapbook of book reviews.
148893
Biographical History
Harvey Chalmers (1890-1971) was an American author, novelist, and short story writer known for his historical fiction relating to early New York State and United States history. Born in Amsterdam, he operated a pearl button factory in New York for many years until the advent of plastic buttons put it out of business. His first novel, West to the Setting Sun, was published in 1943 (the same year he became president of the button company). His other books include Drums Against Frontenac, The Last Stand of the Nez Perce, and The Birth of the Erie Canal (with John H. Flandreau). He also served as consultant to the State Department of Education.
[Adapted from Mr Chalmers' obituary in the New York Times, 8 Oct 1971, p. 46]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Harvey Chalmers Papers consist of several accessions, some of which have been integrated with the main collection and some of which have not. The main collection consists of correspondence-subject files, writings, and memorabilia. Two later accessions, listed at the end of the inventory, contain 1) short stories and 2) correspondence, memorabilia, and writings.
Main collection
Correspondence-subject files contain incoming and outgoing correspondence, covering the years 1938 to 1964, news clippings, holographic notes, and lists of names and addresses. Chalmers' writings include Books, short stories, play (holographic notes for books, original and carbon typescript chapters and short stories, and carbons of a play), Magazine articles, and other Published material. Memorabilia contains photographs and sketches, and an oversized scrapbook containing book reviews complete the main collection.
Short stories (later addition)
This series contains drafts, bound drafts, typescripts, and manuscripts of numerous short stories and books. Some folders also contain criticism and correspondence.
1978 addition
This series contains correspondence (1846-1971), memorabilia (1935-1961), and writings (pamphlets, books, notes, research material, and typescripts).
Note that box numbering restarts with Box 1 for each of the two later additions. When requesting a box please be sure to specify both box number and series to ensure retrieval of the correct items.
Arrangement of the Collection
In the main collection, series are arranged alphabetically by topic (correspondence-subject files), type (memorabilia), or title (writings). Short stories (later addition) are in no particular order. The 1978 addition is arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Chalmers, Harvey.; Authors, American.; New York (State) -- History.; Novelists, American.; Book reviews.; Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Authors.; Novelists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Advertisements, 1949-1950; 1956,; undated (Box 1)
  - Albany Times-Union (Van Olinda), 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Albion Historical-Conversational Club, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - American Heritage Book Company (Alvin Josephy), 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - American News Company, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians (Box 1)
  - Arcade Sesquicentennial and Historical Society, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Argyle Historical Society, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Edward (Radio Hall of Fame), 1955 (Box 1)
  - Articles an Local History, 1960-1961; undated (Box 1)
  - Attica Historical Society, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Atwood, Sarah Jane, 1961; 1963 (Box 1)
  - Augur's Bookstore, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Aurora Historical Society, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Authors' and Writers' Who's Who, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Avery, Mrs. Emmett (Washington State University), 1962 (Box 1)
  - Babcock, Havilah, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Babcock, Ruth Evans, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Baker's, Inc., 1955 (Box 1)
  - Barberg Arnold H., 1960-1962 (Box 1)
  - Barber, Evelyn R., 1950 (Box 1)
  - H. S. Barney Co., 1948-1949; 1955,; 1957,; 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - Barnum, Starr, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Barry, Bobby, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
  - Barry, Bobby, 1955-1958 (Box 1)
  - Beard, Willism H., 1954-1956; 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - Beauchamp Historical Club, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Becker, Mrs. Elizabeth, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Beemer's Stationery, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Bennington Bookshop, 1949-1962 (Box 1)
  - Beta Theta Pi, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Big Springs Historical Society of Caledonia, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Blurbs for How the Irish Built the Erie Canal (Box 1)
  - Book Box and Book Corner, 1947; 1949,; 1956,; 1960 (Box 1)
  - The Book Cellar, 1950-1961 (Box 1)
  - Booklets about Erie Canal and Cayuga Canal (Box 1)
  - Bookman Associates, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Boonville Historical Club, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Boorady's Book Store, 1952; 1960 (Box 1)
  - Brackett's Book Store, 1947-1956; 1960-1962 (Box 1)
  - Brattleboro Informer, 1955; 1956 (Box 1)
  - Bresee's Department Store, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Brigg's Drug Store, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Brighton Historical Society, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - British Book Service, Ltd., 1949 (Box 1)
  - Broadway Book Shop, 1949-1955; 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - Brockport History Club, 1969-1961 (Box 1)
  - Broome County Historical Society, Inc., 1960 (Box 1)
  - Brotherhood of Trainmen, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Bruce, Lewis, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Brundige, Mrs. Lorraine, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Bryan, B, F., 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - Buffalo Evening News, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Buffalo Historical Society, 1960; 1964 (Box 1)
  - Burns, Mrs. J. E., 1947 (Box 1)
  - Burr, Rev. Hugh, undated (Box 1)
  - Caedman, Sister A. S. A., Cambridge Historical Society, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Campbell, Donald (N. Y. State Assembly), 1957; 1960,; 1963 (Box 1)
  - Campbell, W. S., 1947 (Box 1)
  - Canadian Authors' Association, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Cannon, Curtis, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - Cape Vincent Historical Club, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Carey, Booth, 1952-1958; 1961 (Box 1)
  - Carr, Arthur A., 1960 (Box 1)
  - Carroll, Ralph, 1950; 1962 (Box 1)
  - Carter, Mrs. George, 1947-1952; 1954,; 1956,; 1959-1962 (Box 1)
  - Casey, Mr. M. F., 1949-1950 (Box 1)
  - Castile Historical Society (Box 1)
  - Cattaraugus-New Albion Historical Society, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Caxton Printers, Ltd., 1959-1963 (Box 2)
  - Cayuga County Historical Society (Box 2)
  - Chalmers, Arthur (father), 1947-1962; undated; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Chalmers, Arthur II (Box 2)
  - Chalmers, Mrs. Harvey (wife) (Box 2)
  - Chalmers, Shirley (daughter) (Box 2)
  - Chamberlain, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Chambrun, Jacques, 1948; 1953,; 1959 (Box 2)
  - Channel Press, 1959-1961 (Box 2)
  - Chapman, Edward A., 1950 (Box 2)
  - Chariton, Mrs. Helen (Canastota Public Library), 1960; 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - The Charlotte Inn, undated (Box 2)
  - Chautaugua County Historical Society, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Chemung County Historical Society, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Chenango County Historical Society, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Cherry Valley Historical Association, Inc., 1960 (Box 2)
  - Clapp's Book and Stationery Store, 1947-1951; 1953-1960 (Box 2)
  - Cleary, William E., 1960 (Box 2)
  - Cleworth, Thomas S., 1962 (Box 2)
  - Clinton Book Shop, 1950-1951; 1953,; 1957,; 1959-1960 (Box 2)
  - Clinton County Historical Society, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Cole, Lois Dwight (Whittlesey House), 1947; 1949 (Box 2)
  - Columbia County Historical Society, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Colombo, John Robert (Box 2)
  - Community Book Shop, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Community Historical Association (Medina, New York), 1960 (Box 2)
  - Concord Historical Society, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Constable Hall Association, Inc., 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Cooney, Edward J., 1960 (Box 2)
  - Cornell Campus Store, Inc., 1954 (Box 2)
  - Corner Book Store, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - Corner Cigar Store, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Corning-Painted Post Historical Society, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, personal, D-W (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, unidentifiable (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, unsigned, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Cortland County Historical Society, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Covington Historical Society, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Cross, Gorham, 1947-1952; 1954,; 1960 (Box 2)
  - Crysler, Mrs. Grant, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Cunningham (Oneida County Historical Society), 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Cunnings (Bookstore), 1949-1960 (Box 2)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Dean, Leon W., 1955 (Box 2)
  - De Graff's Book Store, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Democrat and Chronicle (Arch Merrill), 1950 (Box 2)
  - Devin-Adair Company, 1959-1960 (Box 2)
  - DeWitt Historical Society of Tompkins County, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - F. G. Diefendorf and Son, 1947-1960 (Box 2)
  - The Dominick Fund, Inc., 1961 (Box 2)
  - Donahue, Jane, 1956; 1958-1962 (Box 2)
  - Doran, James R., 1956 (Box 2)
  - H. M. Douglass and Son, 1949-1950; 1953,; 1955-1957,; 1959 (Box 2)
  - Dresbach, Glenn Ward, 1952-1953; 1959-1961 (August) (Box 2)
  - Dresbach, Glenn Ward, 1971-1962 (September); 1963 (Box 2)
  - Drew, Mrs. Nelson F., 1950 (Box 3)
  - Drew Stationery, Inc., 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Drums Against Frontenac, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Dunham, Harvey L., 1954 (Box 3)
  - Dunne, Judge Matthew, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Durgin, Louise (Mrs. James H.), 1964 (Box 3)
  - Dutchess County Historical Society, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Dutch Settlers' Society of Albany, 1960 (Box 3)
  - E. W. Edwards and Son, 1960 (Box 3)
  - The Elma Historical Society, 1960 (Box 3)
  - J. and J. W. Elsworth Company, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
  - Ennis, Dr. David, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Erie County Historical Society, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Evans, Mrs Richard, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Everyday Book Shop, 1949-1950; 1953-1955,; 1957,; 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - The Farmer's Museum, Inc, 1947-1948; 1960 (Box 3)
  - Fee, James Alger, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Field and Stream, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Fitt, Rev. Frank, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Flick, Hugh M., 1947; 1949,; 1951,; 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Flynn, Arthur G., 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Old Fort Niagra Association, 1947-1952; 1955,; 1961 (Box 3)
  - Old Fort Ticonderoga Museum, 1957; 1960 (Box 3)
  - Frair's Book Store, 1947; 1949-1951,; 1953-1954,; 1956-1957,; 1959-1961 (Box 3)
  - Fuller, S. Je, Jr., 1947 (Box 3)
  - Fulton County Historical Society, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Genealogies on Platt and Talcott Families (Box 3)
  - Genesee County Historical Federation, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Geneva Historical Society, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Geraldson, Dr. Carroll M., 1953 (Box 3)
  - Gray, E. L., 1959 (Box 3)
  - (Morgan) Guarantee Trust Company, 1947-1948; 1956-1962 (Box 3)
  - Hayes, Jack, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Historical Societies, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Historical Societies, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Historical Societies, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Hyde Park Historical Association, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Idaho Historical Society, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Interlacken Historical Society, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Ives, Irving M., 1947 (Box 3)
  - The John Day Company, Inc., 1959 (Box 3)
  - Jones, Dr. Louis C., 1960 (Box 3)
  - Lane, Edith A., 1949 (Box 3)
  - Latherst Pyne, 1949-1951; 1953-1957,; 1960 (Box 3)
  - Lavender's Book Store, 1947; 1949-1952,; 1955-1957,; 1959-1961 (Box 4)
  - Lee, Charles, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Liberty Mutual Insurance Company, 1956; 1958,; 1961-1963 (Box 4)
  - Lists of names and addresses (Box 4)
  - Little, Mr. and Mrs. Theodore, 1962 (March-May) (Box 4)
  - Little, Mr. and Mrs. Theodore, 1962 (June-December) (Box 4)
  - The Little Book Shop, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Loy, Rolland J., 1947; 1949-1950 (Box 4)
  - Luce, Edith M., 1947-1949 (Box 4)
  - MacGregor, Prof. D. C., 1955 (Box 4)
  - MacMillan and Company (Canada), 1947 (February-August) (Box 4)
  - MacMillan and Company (Canada), 1947 (September-December) (Box 4)
  - MacMillan and Company (Canada), 1948 (January-September) (Box 4)
  - MacMillan and Company (Canada), 1948 (October-December); 1949 (Box 4)
  - MacMillan and Company (Canada), 1950-1961 (Box 4)
  - Madden, Emily A., 1960 (Box 4)
  - Martin, Mabel A., 1959 (Box 4)
  - Massena Observer, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
  - McCurdy's and Company, 1960-1962 (Box 4)
  - McGrath, Matt, 1948-1949 (Box 4)
  - McGreevy's, 1961-1963 (Box 4)
  - McKelvey, Blake, 1964 (Box 4)
  - McNickle, D'Arcy, 1962 (Box 4)
  - McWhorter, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Mechanics and Farmers' Bank (Douglas Olcott), 1961 (Box 4)
  - Mehar, Barry, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Meeker, J. H., 1951 (Box 4)
  - Merrick, Marion (Mrs. Alden C.), 1950 (Box 4)
  - Merrill, Arch, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
  - Mills, Allison, 1949; 1952-1958,; 1960-1961 (Box 4)
  - Mills, Lawrence and Family, 1947-1950; 1956-1962 (Box 4)
  - Minisink Valley Historical Society, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
  - Mistletop Book Shop, 1949-1963 (Box 4)
  - Mitchell, Margaret, 1937 (Box 4)
  - Monroe-Augur Book Company, 1947-1963 (Box 4)
  - Montgomery County Trust Company, 1947; 1955-1961 (Box 4)
  - Moore, Mrs. E. B., 1962 (Box 4)
  - Moot, Edmund, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
  - Morgan Guarantee Trust Company, See (Morgan) Guarantee Trust Company.
  - Morton, Mrs. J. T., 1960-1961 (Box 4)
  - Mosier, Pauline (Mrs. Duane H.), 1950-1951; 1959 (Box 4)
  - Munger, Clara, 1947; 1949 (Box 4)
  - Mutual Benefit Life Insurance, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Monroe Holler, 1960-1962 (Box 4)
  - Munson Williams Procter Institute, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Nassau Community College, 1960 (Box 4)
  - National Geographic Society, 1947 (Box 4)
  - National Commercial Bank and Trust Company, 1958; 1960-1963 (Box 4)
  - Negus, Donald, undated (Box 5)
  - Nellson, J. G., 1949 (Box 5)
  - News Clippings, 1908; 1946,; 1949-1950 (Box 5)
  - News Clippings, 1956-1957; 1962,; 1966,; undated (Box 5)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1956 (Box 5)
  - New York State (Conservation Dept., Engineering Dept.), 1954; 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - New York State Historical Society, 1947; 1949,; 1951,; 1956,; 1960 (Box 5)
  - Notes-Activities of the Regency (Box 5)
  - Notes-Annual Report on Construction (Box 5)
  - Notes-Clinton, DeWitt (Box 5)
  - Notes-Cooper, Judge William; Eddy, Thomas; Erie (Box 5)
  - Notes-Biographical (Box 5)
  - Notes-Cooper, Eddy, Cunningham (Box 5)
  - Notes-Fox, D.,R. (Box 5)
  - Notes-Biographical (Box 5)
  - Notes-Geddes, Wright, Day (Box 5)
  - Notes-Information on Cities (Box 5)
  - Notes-Livingstone, Robert R. (Box 5)
  - Notes-New York State History (Box 5)
  - Notes-Typescript of Lecture Article; Lecture Notes (Box 5)
  - Notes-Watson; Washington, George (Box 5)
  - Notes-Western Inland Lock Navigation Co.; Weston, William (Box 5)
  - Notes-Miscellaneous Notes (Box 5)
  - Ockenfel's Book Store, 1960-1962 (Box 5)
  - O'Connor, George E., 1966 (Box 5)
  - O'Donnell's Bookstore, 1949-1950; 1955,; 1960-1961 (Box 5)
  - The Old Print Shop, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Oneida County-Bibliography and Research (Box 5)
  - O'Reilly's Book Store, 1949-1951; 1960 (Box 5)
  - Otto Ulrich Company, Inc., 1949-1953; 1959-1964 (Box 5)
  - Overland, Helen Howard, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Pardee, Henry S., 1947-1962 (Box 5)
  - Parker, Arthur C., 1948-1953 (Box 6)
  - Pennsylvania Historical Association, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - T. H. Perrin and Company, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Peterson, Bert, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Phelps, William Lyen (Box 6)
  - Platt (lineage for research), 1956; 1960 (Box 6)
  - The Play Shop, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Plaza Book Shop, 1955-1961 (Box 6)
  - Peggs, Richard J., 1950 (Box 6)
  - Posters of Canal (Box 6)
  - Rapp, Marvin A., 1964 (Box 6)
  - Rarick, Ray, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Rawls, Walter H. (Twayne Publishers), 1964; undated (Box 6)
  - Research Correspondence-Birth of the Erie Canal, 1956; 1961-1963 (Box 6)
  - Research Material-How the Irish Built the Erie Ridge Book Shop, 1947-1962 (Box 6)
  - Robinson, Ray M., 1964 (Box 6)
  - Robinson and Cunningham, Inc., 1950-1951; 1953,; 1955 (Box 6)
  - Edson E. Robinson, Inc., 1949; 1953-1962 (Box 6)
  - Rohloff, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Russell, Kay, 1960-1962 (Box 6)
  - Russell and Wait, 1947-1962 (Box 6)
  - Rydell, James, 1964 (Box 6)
  - The Ryerson Press (Toronto), 1950; 1955-1956 (Box 6)
  - St. Regis Trading Post, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Saltzman, —, 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Sanger's Book Store, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Sebring, Lewis B., Jr., 1950 (Box 6)
  - Seely Conover Company, 1950; 1956,; 1958,; 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Smith, Richard R., 1950; 1954 (Box 6)
  - Spree's Stationery, 1955; 1960 (Box 6)
  - State University of New York, 1960; 1964 (Box 6)
  - Stock's Stationery Store, 1957; 1960 (Box 6)
  - Stuart, John, 1943 (Box 6)
  - Survey Profiles (Box 6)
  - Syracuse University, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Taga Book Shop, 1950; 1955,; 1960 (Box 6)
  - Tapply, H. G., 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - Taylor, Lois (Mrs. Allan), 1947 (Box 6)
  - Terwilliger, Ein (Mrs. Fred), 1960 (Box 6)
  - Thompson's Gift Shop, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Thurston, Theodore, 1951-1964 (Box 6)
  - Tidewater Oil Company, 1958-1960 (Box 6)
  - Tilton's Book Shop, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Time Magazine, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Timms Libraries, 1949-1950 (Box 6)
  - Timms Libraries, 1951-1957; 1960 (Box 6)
  - Troy, New York, Times Record, Troy Record, 1949-1950; 1955 (Box 6)
  - Triangle Bookshop, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Tribune Press, 1949-1950 (Box 6)
  - Treadeau, Francis, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Turner, Robert, 1947; 1950 (Box 6)
  - Union Book Company, 1950; 1953,; 1955,; 1958-1961 (Box 6)
  - Union Electric Company, 1957 (Box 6)
  - University of North Carolina Press, 1953 (Box 6)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1951; 1961 (Box 6)
  - U.S. Dept. of Interior, Dept. of Treasury, 1954-1955 (Box 6)
  - Upper Susquehanna Historical Society, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Van de Water, Frederick F., 1946-1947 (Box 7)
  - Van Gorden Company, 1949-1950; 1959,; 1960,; 1961 (Box 7)
  - Van Fleet, Albert H., 1959 (Box 7)
  - Van Voris, Arthur H., 1957; 1958 (Box 7)
  - Vermont Book Shop, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Volwiller, Prof. A. T., 1948; 1951,; 1954,; 1956 (Box 7)
  - Vroman, Myron, 1947-1950; 1953,; 1955-1956,; 1959-1960 (Box 7)
  - Vrooman, John J., 1950; 1959 (Box 7)
  - Wachusett Shirt Company, 1947 (Box 7)
  - Station WAGA, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Wagar Drug Company, Inc., 1960 (Box 7)
  - The Wagon Wheel, 1946; 1949,; 1951 (Box 7)
  - Wallace, Crossley W., 1949 (Box 7)
  - Wallace, J. Brougha, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Walter, Mr. and Mrs. George W., 1955-1956; 1960-1963 (Box 7)
  - Warner's Products Company, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Warren, Harold S., 1948; 1951-1955,; 1957,; 1960 (Box 7)
  - Warren, Mrs. Helen, 1949 (Box 7)
  - Warren, Mrs. Willard C., 1949 (Box 7)
  - Waterman, George, 1946-1947; 1950-1951 (Box 7)
  - Waters, Daniel F., 1949-1951 (Box 7)
  - Watertown Times, 1949-1950 (Box 7)
  - Waterville Textile Mills, Inc., 1947 (Box 7)
  - Webster, Prof. Clarence, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Welch, Marvin A., 1947 (Box 7)
  - A. J. Wescott Company, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Western Union Telegram Company, 1947 (Box 7)
  - J. R. Weston Company, 1949-1950; 1955 (Box 7)
  - Whipple, Frank A., 1956; 1960-1961 (Box 7)
  - White, Gerry J., 1947 (Box 7)
  - White, W. Mansfield, 1960 (Box 7)
  - W. M. Whitney and Company, 1949-1950 (Box 7)
  - Widdemer, Margaret, 1952-1953 (Box 7)
  - Wiese, Donald E., 1960 (Box 7)
  - Williams, 1948 (Box 7)
  - Williams, Clarence S. A., 1947; 1962 (Box 7)
  - Williams, Jack R., 1962-1963 (Box 7)
  - Wilson, Edmund L., 1959; 1961 (Box 7)
  - Wilson's Book Store, 1947-1950 (Box 7)
  - Winchester Repeating Arms Company, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Woodworth, Hugh, 1947-1948; 1951,; 1958,; 1960 (Box 7)
  - Woody, A. L., 1948 (Box 7)
  - Woolgar and Roberts, 1947 (Box 7)
  - Worchester Library, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Wright, Richard, 1960-1961 (Box 7)
  - Yale Athletic Association, 1947; 1948,; 1955-1956 (Box 7)
  - Yale University Library, 1960 (Box 7)
  - You Asked For It, 1957 (Box 7)
  - Zicha, Charles, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Ziesenitz, William H., 1947-1952; 1955-1956,; 1960-1962 (Box 7)
  - Zurich General Accident and Liability Insurance Company, Ltd, 1950 (Box 7)
- Books, short stories, play
  - Afterglow
    - Part I, Part II revised (Box 8)
    - Part III revised (Box 8)
  - April 1817
    - Chapters 1-7 (Box 8)
    - Chapters 1-7 (Box 8)
  - "Back Street" (Box 8)
  - "Belling the Cat" (Box 8)
  - "A Change of Mind" (Box 9)
  - "Country Club" (Box 9)
  - "The Coyote" (Box 9)
  - "Doc Barret's Kind Heart" (Box 9)
  - "Doc Barret's Kind Heart" (Box 9)
  - "Doc Barret's Kind Heart" (Box 9)
  - Drums Against Frontenac (Box 9)
    - Volume I (Box 9)
    - Volume II (Box 9)
    - Volume III (Box 9)
  - Drums Against Frontenac (printed)
    - Volume I (Box 10)
    - Volume II (Box 10)
  - "The Fighting Name" (Box 10)
  - "Footsteps" (with criticism by Alexander) (Box 10)
  - "The Gentlemen of the Rapier" (Box 10)
  - "Honey Moon Mystery", "The Grand Passion", "Through the Looking Glass" (Box 10)
  - How the Irish Built the Erie, notes
    - Synopsis and Outlines (Box 11)
    - Chapter 1 (Box 11)
    - Chapter 2 (Box 11)
    - Chapter 3 (Box 11)
    - Chapter 1 (Box 11)
    - Chapter 2 (Box 11)
    - Chapter 3 (Box 11)
    - Chapters 4 and 5 (Box 11)
    - Chapter 6 (Box 11)
    - Chapter 7 (Box 11)
    - Chapter 8 (Box 11)
  - How the Irish Built the Erie
    - Chapter 1, revised carbon (Box 12)
    - Chapters 1-5 (Box 12)
    - Chapters 6-9 (Box 12)
  - "Irish Eyes keep Smiling" or "Incident of the Trenches" (Box 12)
  - "Mabel Elliott" (Box 12)
  - "The Masterpiece (An Eye for Beauty or Funniest Thing of All)" (Box 12)
  - "Only One Way" (Box 12)
  - "A Parlor Trick" (Box 12)
  - "Pink Lady" (Box 12)
  - "Room-mates" (Box 12)
  - "The Sabine Women" (Box 12)
  - "The Setter Man" (Box 12)
  - "The Sucker Look" (Box 12)
  - "The Swale Collection" (Box 12)
  - "Synthetic Star" (Box 12)
  - "Tan-Bark" (Box 12)
  - "Too Much Dog" (Box 12)
  - "Uncle Bunbury" (Box 12)
  - West to the Setting Sun
    - Chapters 1-3 (Box 13)
    - Chapters 4-6 (Box 13)
    - Chapters 7-9 (Box 13)
    - Chapters 10-12 (Box 13)
    - Chapters 13-14 (Box 13)
    - Chapters 15-16 (Box 13)
    - Chapters 17-18 (Box 13)
    - Chapters 19-20 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 1 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 2 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 3 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 4 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 5 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 6 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 7 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 8 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 9 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 10 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 11 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 12 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 13 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 14 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 15 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 16 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 17 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 18 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 19 (Box 13)
    - Chapter 20 (Box 13)
  - "Where Friendship Ceases" (Box 13)
- Magazine articles
  - The American Field (Box 14)
  - Field and Stream stories (Box 14)
  - Field and Stream, February, 1940 (Box 14)
  - Field and Stream, December, 1937 (Box 14)
  - New England Sportsman (Box 14)
  - New England Sportsman (Box 14)
  - Outdoors; National Sportsman; Hunting and Fishing (Box 14)
- Published material
  - Catalogs, 1943-1950 (Box 15)
  - Catalogs, 1955-1962 (Box 15)
  - Clipping, "How the Irish Built the Erie" (Box 15??)
  - Pamphlets (Box 15??)
  - Reviews, undated (Box 15)
  - Photographs and Sketches (Box 15)
  - Publicity Photographs (Box 15)
- Memorabilia
  - Scrapbook (mostly reviews)
- Short stories (later addition)
  - Man of Meung; correspondence; criticism (Box 1)
    "The Man of Meung," typed copy, 18 pages
    "The Man of Meung," typed revision (1929), 26 pages
    3-page typed letter of criticism by Milton Ling, dated October 7, 1929
    2-page typed letter, signed "S.B.", undated
  - Uncle Bunbury; criticism (Box 1)
    "Uncle Bunbury," typed first copy, 25 pages
    2-page typed letter of criticism by Milton Ling, dated February 12, 1930
  - The Coyote (Box 1)
    typed copy, 30 pages